Music is a universal language.
音乐是一种世界通用的语言。
In every culture and country, you will find music.
在每一种文化、每一个国家，你都能找到音乐。
It is vitally important across the globe and has the potential to bring people together in peace and harmony.
音乐在全世界都极其重要，并且有可能让人们和平、和谐地相聚在一起。
One of my favorite experiences in music is seeing musicians from different cultures come together and perform as a group.
在音乐方面，我最喜欢的经历之一，就是看到来自不同文化的音乐人走到一起，作为一个整体同台演出。
When each culture brings its own unique qualities to the group, an entirely new sound is achieved.
当每种文化都为这个整体带来自己独特的特质时，就会形成一种全新的声音。
This can create extraordinary results.
这能创造出非凡的成果。
People can communicate with each other using music as the common language.
人们可以把音乐当作共同语言，彼此交流。
One common musical thread between cultures is known as the pentatonic scale.
不同文化之间有一条共同的音乐纽带，被称为五声音阶。
It is astonishing how many cultures share this tool in approaching music.
竟有这么多文化在对待音乐时都使用这一工具，真令人惊讶。
The pentatonic scale consists of five notes: “penta-” meaning five, and “tonic” meaning tone or note.
五声音阶由五个音组成：“penta-”的意思是“五”，“tonic”的意思是“音调”或“音”。
This scale can be found in music everywhere, including that of Native Americans, Africans, and Asians.
这种音阶在世界各地的音乐中都能找到，包括美洲原住民、非洲人和亚洲人的音乐。
It is also found in popular music, blues, jazz, and rock.
流行音乐、布鲁斯、爵士乐和摇滚乐中也能找到它。
Using this five-note scale, musicians from around the globe have a medium through which they can relate, communicate, perform, and ultimately understand each other.
借助这种五声音阶，来自全球各地的音乐人有了一种媒介，可以通过它彼此建立联系、交流、合奏，并最终相互理解。
Music is tied to specific perceptual, mental, and emotional faculties, including language (all societies put words to their songs), motor control (people in all societies dance), sound analysis (all musical systems have a distinct pitch and quality), and aesthetics (their tunes and rhythms are balanced between repetitiveness and chaos).
音乐与特定的感知、心智和情感能力紧密相连，包括语言（所有社会都为自己的歌曲配上歌词）、运动控制（所有社会的人都会跳舞）、声音分析（所有音乐体系都有鲜明的音高和音质）以及美感（其曲调和节奏在重复与混乱之间保持平衡）。
There is no known society that existed without music.
在已知的社会中，没有哪一个是没有音乐的。
Although each culture has its own specific style and approach to music, you will find that the purposes behind music are very similar across the board.
尽管每种文化在音乐上都有自己特定的风格和方式，但你会发现，各种文化中音乐背后的用途都非常相似。
Music essentially serves to express or change emotions.
音乐的本质作用是表达或改变情绪。
It can cheer you up, sadden you, anger you or excite you.
它能让你振奋，让你悲伤，让你愤怒，也能让你兴奋。
Music is often ceremonial: used in religion, ceremony, and celebration.
音乐常常带有仪式性：用于宗教活动、仪式和庆典。
Music can simply be recreational: entertaining, joyful and fun.
音乐也可以纯粹是消遣性的：娱乐身心、令人愉快、充满乐趣。
Any way you have used music, it is almost certain that every other culture has used music in the very same way.
无论你以何种方式用过音乐，几乎可以肯定，其他每一种文化都以完全相同的方式用过音乐。
And that is something that bonds all of us.
而正是这一点把我们所有人联系在一起。
We all share a deep love for music and it has the power to unite us.
我们都对音乐怀有深深的热爱，而音乐有力量把我们团结起来。